noozhawk.com 2008-05-02

# Noozhawk - Terms of Use

## Privacy Policy

Welcome to Noozhawk, a news and information Web site owned and operated by Malamute Ventures LLC in Santa Barbara, Calif. We are committed to protecting your right to privacy, and this policy explains how we do it.

### Personally Identifiable Information

Noozhawk will explicitly ask you when we need information that personally identifies you or allows us to contact you. Generally, such personal information is requested when you seek a particular service or information from us or one of our business partners, advertisers and affiliates. We do not sell, rent or market your personally identifiable information.

We maintain business relationships with certain third-party service partners. These partners allow us to offer you a broader array of services than we could provide you on our own, and they assist us in our site operation. We and our partners may use your general demographic information to operate Noozhawk and refine the services we offer.

Noozhawk expects its business partners, advertisers and affiliates to respect your privacy. These third parties, and other content providers accessible through our site, may have their own privacy and information policies and practices. Noozhawk is not responsible for the actions or policies of such third parties. You should review the third parties' applicable privacy policies when providing information on a feature or page operated by a third party.

### Traffic Data

Like most Web sites, Noozhawk collects and logs information automatically and through the use of electronic tools that may be transparent to you, such as your IP address, the name and location of your Internet service provider, the type and version of your browser, the length of time you stay on Noozhawk's Web site, search queries, your clickstream data, the location that referred you to Noozhawk, and the average number of pages viewed. We analyze this information and then discard it. We may aggregate information about visitors and traffic and may share the results with our business partners, advertisers and affiliates. We will not disclose your individual identity or personally identifiable data that you supply us without your permission and will only use it to contact you. Further, logging your IP address does not in and of itself provide us with your name, e-mail address or home or work address.

### Cookies 

A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. We make limited use of cookies to personalize your use of Noozhawk and to facilitate the log-in process for registered users. You have the ability to modify your Web browser to decline cookies if you so choose, but doing so may limit your access to Noozhawk and may prevent you from registration. Our business partners, advertisers and affiliates also have the ability to assign their cookies to you if you visit their sites. Noozhawk does not control third-party use of this technology or the resulting information, and is not responsible.

### Children's Privacy

Noozhawk will not directly solicit personal information from children age 13 years old or younger without first obtaining a Parental Consent Form signed by a parent or legal guardian. The sole exception to this is our mailing lists. If a child under 13 signs up for our e-letters or any of our mailing lists, he or she will remain subscribed unless a parent or legal guardian asks us to remove the name, or the child elects to opt out. At no time will we provide personal information from children age 13 years old or younger for other companies' use without first obtaining the consent of a parent or guardian.

Noozhawk strongly recommends parental supervision when a child uses the Internet, particularly when a child enters a forum or uses e-mail. We also encourage parents to instruct their children not to give out personal information in these areas.

### E-letters and E-Bulletins

If you sign up to receive Noozhawk's e-letters, you may also receive infrequent other Member announcements from us. Users can choose to unsubscribe, or opt out, from any new mailing lists we create, at any time, by following the unsubscribe instructions found in each e-mail.

### Other Sites

Noozhawk contains links to Internet sites operated by others. We cannot control and are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other Web sites.

### Other Disclosure of Personal Information

Noozhawk will not otherwise disclose or make use of personal information without con-sent of the user except (a) as described in this privacy policy; (b) as required by law, court order or as requested by other government or law-enforcement authority; (c) to protect and defend our rights or property or those of our users; or (d) to act as immediately necessary in order to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. This policy does not protect information you post to any online bulletin board, chat room, newsgroup, reviews or other public forum within Noozhawk's Web site.

### Security

Noozhawk takes commercially reasonable precautions to protect our users' personally identifiable information collected or maintained by our Web site against loss, unauthorized access and illegal use or disclosure. This information is stored in secure locations.

### Unsubscribe and Data Removal Policies

To unsubscribe from any Noozhawk mailing list, [click here](http://www.noozhawk.com/subscribe.html) or send an e-mail requesting removal to [wmacfadyen@noozhawk.com](mailto:wmacfadyen@noozhawk.com). Please include the list from which you are asking to be removed.

### Further Questions?

If you have any questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy and use of personal information, please contact William M. Macfadyen, Noozhawk founder, publisher and CEO, at [wmacfadyen@noozhawk.com](mailto:wmacfadyen@noozhawk.com).
